They're coming!
他們來了
Right on time!
還挺準時
Is this number 7 of Carbone Alley?
這裡是卡伯恩街七號嗎
Impounded on 16 September 1954
一九五四年九月十六日起
the furniture of Adelina Sbaratti
安得琳娜·思伯拉提的傢俱將被扣押
My wife
我的妻子
...the consignee, on account of an unpaid fine of 28,000 lire
…處罰人，傢俱被抵押罰金28000里拉
28,000 lire is the fine. Procedural fees...
28000里拉是罰金，加上手續費…
interest and costs, etc.
利息和費用 等等雜費
Brings us to 50,780
一共交付50780
Wasn't 28,000 better?
早點付28000不就好了
Well, are you going to pay this 50, 780?
你付不付50780
What, we didn't pay 28 and we pay 50?
我們不付28我們付50
- Where's the consignee? - My wife?
處罰人在哪，我的妻子
She's not here
她不在這裡
I'll take the furniture then
即使這樣我也會把傢俱帶走
Come in, sir
進來吧 先生
Let's see...
讓我們看看…
A walnut table 6x4...
一個6x4大小的胡桃木桌子…
You made a clean sweep. It's out of my hands now
你把所有的東西都搬走了 現在這裡什麼都沒有了
This is a court matter. Make way!
這是法庭的裁定，我們走
We fooled him!
我們把他耍了
He wanted Adelina Sbaratti?
他想要抓到安得琳娜·思伯拉提
That's all you're good at, but it won't get you anywhere
你幹的不錯 可是你不會如願以償的
You're in big trouble now
你現在在大麻煩之中
- What's he after? - He came on Wednesday
- 他接下來要怎樣 - 他週三會來
- Who is he? - Search me
- 他是誰 - 我找找
I'm Verace, a lawyer, and you're illiterate clowns!
我是瓦斯，一個律師 而你們都是目不識丁的小丑
That was no joke, you're in big trouble
這不是開玩笑，你現在有大麻煩了
You'll see when the police come
你看等到警察來了
You'll go to jail for the crime you committed!
你會因為妨礙執法而入獄
What crime?
什麼罪
You violated Art. 384 of the Criminal Code!
你觸犯了第384條法令
That's what you did!
這就是你入獄的理由
Mr Verace!
瓦斯先生
Explain it to us, we're ignorant
恕我們愚鈍，請給我們解釋一下
First you get into trouble, then you come to us lawyers
你先是身陷麻煩之中 然後律師你就到了我們這裡來
But it was only a fine
但是這只是一筆罰金
Which you didn't pay, so they impounded your furniture
你並沒有付清罰金 所以他們要扣壓你的傢俱
And you came up with the smart idea of hiding it
然後你耍個小聰明把傢俱藏起來
But my friend is a bit... needy
不過是因為我的朋友生活很拮据
What did they fine him for?
他們因為什麼原因罰他的款
Selling contraband cigarettes
非法販賣香煙
I'm sorry, my friend, but you're in big trouble
對不起，我的朋友，但是你真的有大麻煩了
But it's not me, it's my wife, a mother of children!
但是不是我，是我的妻子，一群孩子的媽媽
They fined her. The furniture's hers, the rent's in her name
他們找到她 這些傢俱是她的 房子也是她的名字租的
Then she'll go to jail
那麼就是她要去監獄了
Don't let him get away. Pasquale, call Adelina!
別讓他離開，帕斯誇來，快去叫安得琳娜來
Mr Verace!
瓦斯先生
Cigarettes!
香煙
English, American, Swiss!
英國的，美國的，瑞典的
English, American, Swiss! Who smokes?
英國的，美國的，瑞典的，誰要啊
Sir! I buy dollars!
先生, 我花錢買的
Adelina, you're the only one who can persuade the lawyer
安得琳娜 你是唯一一個可以勸勸律師的人了
What lawyer?
什麼律師
The bailiff came, and a lawyer says we're in trouble
法警來過了，律師說我們現在有大麻煩了
What kind of trouble?
什麼樣的麻煩
Damn them!
真該死
Hey! Come here, boy!
過來，孩子
- Come see the lawyer? - And let everything bum?
- 去見見律師吧 - 一切都會沒事的
You go, we'll take care of the boy
你走吧，我們幫你照料孩子
- What about my box? - Nobody'll touch it
- 那我這箱煙怎麼辦 -  沒有人會動它的
Damn them!
真該死
Hey, a client! That gentleman's mine
嗨，你們幾個，這個先生是我的客人
English, American, Swiss...
英國的，美國的，瑞典的…
- But ma'am... - Yes, I'm coming!
但是，嗯，是，我就來
What he says is true. If he can't help you, he can't help you
他說的是真的，如果他不能幫助你 他就真的是幫不了你
He wouldn't miss good business
他不會錯過一樁好買賣的
But he may just be saying that because he's angry
但是他也許只是因為生氣才這麼說
I've told you once, please go away
我再跟你們說一次，請離開這裡
If you let us see him, we'll give you something
如果你讓我們見見他，我們會給你點小意思
Word of honour, I never saw two more deceitful people!
真好笑，我從未見過像你倆這樣的小人
You get it, I won't budge from here
你們給我聽好了，我是不會挪半步的
- Carmelo... - At last! Come in
- 卡梅羅… - 後面是誰，請進
Who are you? Where are you going?
妳是誰，妳想要幹什麼
- That way - Let's go
- 那邊 - 我們走
You can't go in, is that clear?
你不能進去，你們什麼意思啊
- Where is he? - Mr Verace, help us!
- 他在哪 - 瓦斯先生，救救我們
She can't go to jail!
她不能進監獄
I was fined for selling cigarettes
我被發現販賣香煙
You know how long it takes to make 28,000 lire?
你知道被罰28000里拉意味著什麼
Days... weeks even
數天…甚至是數周
Out there, rain or sun
呆在一個地方，風吹日曬
My husband's been out of work
我的丈夫無法工作
since he was drafted. How can we get by?
自從被他管轄後，我們該如何為生
Then a creep comes along and arrests you
然後還想要逮捕你
No, wait a minute, they can't arrest her
不，等等，他們不能逮捕她
What?
什麼
She's breeding!
她現在懷孕了
They can't arrest her, she's breeding!
他們不能逮捕她，她懷孕了
They can't arrest her, get it? She's breeding!
他們不能逮捕她，明白嗎，她懷孕了
They can't jail her for that crime. She's breeding
他們不能因此罪名把她關進監獄 因為她懷孕了
Have you heard? They can't arrest her
你聽到了嗎，他們不能逮捕她
Why not?
為什麼不
She's breeding
因為她懷孕了
Yes, she's breeding!
是的，因為她懷孕了
She's breeding, she's breeding, cha-cha-cha...
她懷孕了，她懷孕了
I have an American specialty, painless childbirth!
我有美式特效的無痛分娩
- Good luck! - Same to you!
- 祝你好運 - 也祝你好運
Here they are, nice and fresh
這是你們的，新鮮可口的的
Mark it. They're hot, they're hot!
剛出爐的，還熱乎，還熱乎
The lawyer must know. A pregnant woman can't be arrested
律師當然知道 孕婦是不能被逮捕的
until after the baby's born
直到孩子出生後
Plus 6 months for nursing
加上六個月的哺乳期
Kids are a great thing, a gift of Providence
孩子多麼的可愛，是神的眷顧賜予的禮物
although I never had the pleasure
即使我從來沒有這個榮幸
Is it my fault?
是我的錯嗎
I have what it takes! But we won't go into that
我該做的都做了，可是我們仍然沒有懷上
I'm only saying that the best thing in the world
我想說這是世界上做美好的事情
is when a man comes home and his wife says she wants a baby
是當一個男人回到家的時候 他的妻子對他說她想要個孩子
"Heart, ungrateful heart..."
心，忘恩負義的心
Well, what's the joke?
有什麼好笑的
I'd been drafted...
我曾經被派遣到…
No, let me tell it
不，讓我說
We were going together and... well, it happened
我們在一起了，然後…就發生了
"Carmelo, how can I tell Mom?"
卡梅羅，我該怎麼跟媽媽說
This idiot was all happy. "Are you really sure?"
這個笨蛋總是很開心，『你確定』？
"I'll see a midwife tonight." "But I can't get a pass"
我今晚會去和助產士見面 不過我不確定可以
"If it's a definite, I'll come and sing outside the barracks"
如果能定下來，我就在外面唱歌
So that's it!
就是這樣
"Ungrateful Heart" all night
「忘恩負義的心」 整晚
I didn't sleep a wink.
我整晚未合眼
We were married soon after
我們之後就結婚了
Mom was against it."Adelina, I can't give you a cent"
媽媽反問我「安得琳娜 我不會給你一分錢的」
"Carmelo's broke and I have 15 kids. What if you take after me?
卡梅羅生活潦倒，我又已經有15個孩子了 如果你是我你該怎麼做
"Mom, we'll be careful"
「媽媽，我們會小心的」
You didn't keep your word and now you're pregnant again
你沒有履行你的諾言，你現在又懷孕了
Yes, just look at it
是的，快瞧瞧
I could have gone to jail
不然我早進監獄了
The baby's due any day... A short rest...
孩子到來的某天…短暫休息之後…
July, August, September, November, December
七月、八月、九月、十一月、十二月
Carmelo, you'll have to get busy at Christmas
卡梅羅，你在聖誕節的時候會忙起來
Right
是的
Here I am
我時刻準備著
- Merry Christmas! - Merry Christmas
- 聖誕快樂
- Good night! Merry Christmas! - Thank you
- 晚安，聖誕快樂 - 謝謝你
Good night, Mom. Merry Christmas
晚安媽媽，聖誕快樂
All on my own... you have things to do
我以為AA…你們已經有事情忙呢
- Mom, I explained. - I understand
- 媽媽，我跟你解釋過了 - 我明白
We'll have dinner together tomorrow. Oh, I nearly forgot!
我們明天會一起吃飯，我差點忘記了
Granny's made some ointment for your chilblains
奶奶給你做了些治療凍瘡的藥膏
Do I put it on at night?
整晚敷著它嗎
Yes, rub it on when he's in bed
是的，當他上床的時候給他擦
Thanks, Mom. See you tomorrow
謝謝媽媽，明天見
Take care. Merry Christmas again
路上小心，聖誕快樂
Come and celebrate!
回來慶祝
Amedeo's brought a big cake from Milan
阿米尼奧從米蘭買了一個大蛋糕回來
They're all waiting for you
大家都在等你們呢
Pasquale, it's Christmas. I don't want to go to jail
帕斯誇來，現在是聖誕節，我不想去監獄
I get it, you'll have a better Christmas than us
我明白了，你會有一個比我們更好的聖誕節
Stop that! Get moving!
別說了，快走吧
Who lives here?
誰住在這裡
Adelina Sbaratti. I'm here, come in
安得琳娜·思伯拉提，我在這兒，請進
The term's up, it's time for you vacation. You're under arrest
你的假期結束了，你被捕了
What does that mean?
這是什麼意思
The doctor's certificate is on the table
醫生證明書在桌子上
If you want it, help yourself
如果你想看，就自己去看看
Or come back in a few months and you'll find two of them
或者幾個月後再來，並一次拿兩份
- Congratulations - Thank you
- 恭喜你 - 謝謝
See how well he's learned? English, American, Swiss
看他學的多好，英國的、美國的、瑞典的
Swiss!
瑞典
How cute he is!
他好可愛啊
The cops... The cops!
警察，警察
Go ahead, arrest me! I have another five months
過來啊，抓我啊，我還有另外五個月
50 lire's worth of chestnuts
買五十里拉的栗子
Sorry, huh? The usual favor...
對不起，通常的話…
Right, let's see
對了，讓我們看看
Forget it, for a few chestnuts...
不用了，只是一點栗子
Thank you
謝謝
- I can't make it out - You wrote it
- 我看不明白 - 是你寫的阿
The best I could
我最好
Darn reading and writing!
學學閱讀和寫作
Delivered on October 28... I was selling prickly pears then
十月二十八號來的…我那會兒還在賣刺梨
Six months' nursing. October, November, December...
六個月哺乳期，十月、十一月、十二月
Her reprieve ends in May, when cherries come out
她緩刑到五月底，櫻桃成熟的時候
It's January now. There's time
現在是一月份，還有些時間
Carmelo, if you need any help, feel free!
卡梅羅，如果你需要任何幫助，儘管開口
Pasquale, if you need a baby, I do home catering!
帕斯誇來，如果你需要一個孩子 我會幫你搞定的
Two pounds of cherries
兩磅的櫻桃
Cherries! Cherries!
櫻桃，櫻桃
A couple of cherries for her...
給她裝些櫻桃
- The certificate? - The certificate!
- 證明書
- Another child? - Another child
- 還有孩子
That's four. How many more?
那是四個，另外還有多少
All the ones that come!
所有的都在這
Maria, don't be late! And take the umbrella
瑪利亞，別太晚了，把傘帶著吧
All right, Mom
好的，媽媽
Open wide, here comes the fuel!
張大嘴，能量來啦
Have they finished, Pasquale?
他們都吃完了嗎，帕斯誇來
It's all gone, look!
都吃完了，看
Make me a pacifier for Caterina
讓我親親卡特娜吧
Coming up
過來
I'll make it later. Let me quiet the kids down first
我一會兒來弄，讓我先把孩子們安頓下來
Come here, kids. Pasquale's got something nice for you
過來，孩子們，帕斯誇來有好東西給你們
Easy now, one at a time
現在，人人有份
One for you, one for you... and we'll keep these for later
你一個，你一個… 你們先拿著，我們一會兒來玩
Now be good while I make a pacifier for Caterina
現在去親親卡特娜
Nunziatina, let me tie a bow in your hair
紐澤阿緹娜，讓我把你頭髮扎個蝴蝶結上去
You must have a bow
你必須扎個蝴蝶結
No bow, no candy
不要蝴蝶結，就不給糖果
Where's Carmelo?
卡梅羅哪去了
He's in a bad way
他最近身體不適
With seven kids it's a regular fanfare all night
一口氣生七個孩子，整夜都生龍活虎
I sent him off to Mom's to get an hour's sleep
我讓他到媽媽那裡去睡覺休息一段時間
How pretty you look! Now Pasquale will give you some more candy
你看起來多漂亮啊 現在帕斯誇來會再給你些糖果
Here you are
給你，拿著
This fanfare seems to do you good, though
你現在什麼都很好是吧
You're prettier than ever now, bless you
你現在美艷絕倫，保佑你
Kids are good for me. Some women fall apart after the first
孩子對我很好 一些女人生過第一胎之後就不行了
But not me. Look... seven kids
不過，看看我，七個孩子
The cough medicine, I forgot
我差點忘記止咳藥了
I don't want it
我不要
You'll take it. It was bought and it has to be used
你必須喝，花錢買回來了必須喝
You'll take it
你必須喝
Come here or I'll smack you!
快過來，不然就打你了
Not like that. Kindness gets you everywhere. Let me try
別那樣對他，溫柔點才能行，讓我試試
Come out!
過來
Come to Uncle Pasquale...
來帕斯誇來叔叔這裡...
Go to hell!
去死吧
What, to your Uncle Pasquale? Come on now
什麼，對帕斯誇來叔叔這樣，快過來
What did he do?
他做什麼了
He bit me... it's nothing
他咬我…沒什麼
I'll fix him! He'll come out!
我會好好修理他，快出來
Get out from under there!
從下面給我出來
I've got him!
我抓住他了
Hold him tight!
抓緊他
Don't let him go!
別讓他跑了
My name's not Adelina Sbaratti
我的名字 就不叫安得琳娜·思伯拉提
if you don't take it
你要是不吃藥
We can't throw money out of the window like that
我們不能把錢就像從窗戶中丟掉那樣
For a tantrum! 400 lire!
浪費了400里拉
Come on now, out you go! Go outside
過來，你們出去，都到外面去
Here, buy yourselves a lollypop
哪,給你們去買些棒棒糖吧
I'll send them to school
我會把他們都送到學校去
Now come to bed like a good girl
現在像個乖寶寶那樣到床上去睡覺吧
Adelina, she has to eat something
安得琳娜，她得吃點東西
What? She had two plates of pasta! Put her to bed
什麼，她已經吃了兩份意大利面了 把她抱上床吧
She's fast asleep already... Let's go
她已經很快睡著了…我們走
This is red hot
這麼熱啊
I'd keep you company but I have things to do
我仍然會常常來幫忙得，不過我也有事要忙
Off you go, and thank you. What a good father you'd make
你走吧，謝謝你，你是一個好父親
Pasquale! Are you crazy?
帕斯誇來，你瘋了嗎
I'm sorry, I got a bit carried away
對不起，我有點得意忘形
I'm sorry!
對不起
I can't, Mom, I can't! Can't you hear them?
我不能，媽媽，我不能 你難道聽不到他們的聲響嗎
I came here to sleep. Have a word with Don Antonio
我過來睡覺，我去和旦·安東尼奧說說
But they have to work. I pay next to nothing a month here
不過他們必須要幹活 我下個月在這的房租才能全免
Don Antonio, will you be long?
旦·安東尼奧，你們還要干多久
Another 10 minutes, then we break for lunch
再過十分鐘，我們就到午餐休息了
But if you go on hammering?
不過接下來你如果繼續發出捶打聲
Don't worry, we'll let Carmelo get an hour's sleep
別擔心 我們會讓卡梅羅有一個小時的休息時間
Thank you
謝謝
Look how long he's keeping me waiting!
看看他讓我等了多久
I'll come at 9, he says. It's 10:30 and he hasn't shown
他說我會在九點的時候來 現在已經十點半了，他還沒有露面
At last! It took you long enough. Come on!
最後，你終於來了，來吧
I've come from Porta Capuana
我來自波塔·卡普阿娜
Come on...
來吧
- So? - I've come from Porta Capuana
- 什麼？ - 我來自波塔·卡普阿娜
No, it's not me! This way!
不是，不是我，這邊
Came in, hurry up!
快進來，快點
No, over here... on the bed
不，不是這…是床上
You want a boy or a girl?
你想要一個男孩還是一個女孩
Anything goes, as long as it's a sure thing
無所謂，能確定有就行
That costs 50 lire more
那就要多50里拉
All right
好吧
All right, ring the bell. - Now?
- 好吧，請搖鈴 - 現在
Tomorrow?
明天
Where does your husband sleep?
你丈夫睡哪邊
Here
這裡
Ring the bell, please.
請搖鈴
I can't take any more!
我再也受不了了
Right, you must look after yourself
好吧，你必須要照顧好你自己
The first thing is sleep. I'll make you some herb tea
第一件事是睡覺，我會給你做一點草藥茶
Herb tea, when my life's been hell for three years?
草藥茶，當我妻子在地獄受苦的三年
What a calamity...
遭天譴的
It's always the same: get busy, the nursing term's over!
總是這樣，哺乳期一結束就忙起來了
Go to bed early! The police! Turn the light out!
快上床，警察，把燈關上
And all that on a bowl of soup a day. I'm not made of iron
每天只有一碗湯，我不是鐵打的
Doing it to order is one thing, but this is continuous
每天都是力行公事，但是總是持續毫不停歇
You do look peaked
你看起來很憔悴呢
That follows
就是說啊
Dizzy spells, wobbly legs
頭昏眼花，四肢無力
And if you must know, I've fainted twice in the street
而且你要知道我已經在街上昏倒兩次了
And the more I become a wreck, the more she's at me
我身體越來越差，可是她卻越來越好
How pretty she's grown, Mom. She's blossomed like a rose
她生的如此美麗，媽媽 她像一朵含苞待放的玫瑰
She's bleeding you dry. You've grown as ugly as an ape
你卻這麼差 越來越像一隻猴子一般乾巴巴的
Let the rose find herself
讓那個玫瑰花知道知道自己是誰
someone to make her breed to order
找別人代替她例行公事吧
I'll kill her... if anything like that happens
我會殺了她…如果她對我不忠誠
Carmelino...
卡梅羅
Carmelo, give me a hand
卡梅羅，過來幫幫忙
A chicken, pasta and wine, 100 lire. What number?
雞肉，意大利面和酒，100里拉，想要幾號
Give me 89
給我89號
Who wants a number? Buy a lottery ticket!
誰要選個好號碼，快來買張彩票吧
Darn it, I was dead certain this time. Two weeks!
真見鬼，我最近像行屍走肉一般，整整兩周
I even made an appointment with the doctor for the certificate
我都跟醫生預約了一個時間去開證明
And instead I feel lousy. I guess I'm not used to it any more
我覺得很糟糕 我覺得我以後都沒辦法再這麼幹了
- Beat it! - What do you mean?
- 滾開 - 你什麼意思
I mean I was late and there's no baby
我是說太遲了，我還沒有懷孕
How can I help it? How can I help it?
我有什麼辦法，我有什麼辦法
Are you trying to send the poor girl to jail?
你是要把這個可憐的女孩送到監獄嗎
- You can't think that! - We do think that!
- 你不能這麼說 - 我們就這麼覺得的
Look at my husband, and learn!
看看我的丈夫，學著點
- You can go in - Thank you
- 你可以去了 - 謝謝
Come in, come in
進來,進來
Sit down
坐下
Sorry to bother you, but I always give you fresh cigarettes
對不起麻煩你 不過我給你的一直都是新鮮的香煙吧
So I thought you'd give me preferential treatment too
所以我認為你也會給我以優待
Of course... And how's business?
當然了…生意怎麼樣
I can't complain
還不錯呢
What's it about?
有什麼能幫忙的
You tell him, Carmelo, you're the man
你告訴他，卡梅羅，你是一個男人
He's shy
他很害羞
A doctor's like a confessor
醫生像一個傾聽者一樣
Doctor, I...
醫生，我…
Since we got married, it's been continuous
自從我們結婚了，房事就一直持續
There's never been a break in this... current
直到最近也從未停歇過
Seven kids, and I'm still nursing
七個孩子，我仍然在哺乳期
It's not my fault, Doctor. The will is there
這不是我的錯，醫生，事情擺在那裡
You bet
你好意思說
We married for love. It's obvious the will was there
我們結婚是因為愛情，這是很顯而易見的
But if this goes on, who'll keep the kids?
不過如果這樣繼續下去，誰來照顧這些孩子
He's out of work, I have to provide for everyone
他沒有工作，我不得不養家餬口
Your wife's right
你妻子是對的
Sure, but I'm right too
當然了，我也沒有錯啊
We're not animals. Your wife's pretty, you're in love
我們不是動物，你太太那麼美麗 你們彼此深愛對方
but you ought to control yourself, my boy
但是你應該控制好你自己，我的孩子
It's not that I don't feel the urge. I do feel it
不是這樣的，我並沒有覺得衝動 我只是覺得持續房事
Stifle it. So you don't want any more children?
快要讓我窒息了，所以你不再想要孩子了
No, quite the opposite. But he doesn't work any more
不，正好相反，但是他已經不再和我做了
Just a minute... The urge is there
等一下，我對她有慾望的
I don't understand. What is it you want?
我不明白，那你們到底要怎樣
Another child!
再要一個孩子
So you came to have your husband examined?
所以你來是為了你丈夫的檢查
Yes, sir
是的，先生
Come over here them
你過來
Sit down here
坐在這
Take your jacket off
把夾克脫了
- The urge is there - I feel the urge too
- 我有性慾啊 - 我也知道你有性慾啊
Cross your legs
兩腿交叉
His leg reacts, it moves
他腿部的膝跳反射，很正常
What do I care if his leg moves?
我為什麼關心他膝蓋正不正常
You're slightly anaemic. Let's check your blood pressure
你有點輕微的貧血，讓我量量你的血壓
There's nothing wrong with him, he's just very tired
他沒什麼問題，只是有點疲勞過度
You're undernourished
而且還營養不良
Is it serious?
真的嗎
There's no need to worry, it's a very minor thing
不用擔心，這個沒什麼大不了的
- Pressure, 80 - Is that good?
- 血壓80 - 是健康的嗎
No, bad. He's run down
不，不是，他有點精疲力竭了
What should he do?
那他該怎麼辦
You don't whip a tired horse, you put him in the stable
你不能對一隻疲乏的馬兒策馬揚鞭 你要讓他在馬廄中休息
Let him be for three months. He'll take treatment
讓他休養三個月，他要接受治療
eat nourishing food, and you'll have the baby next year
吃滋補的食物 而你們等到明年就會有孩子了
Hello, Adelina. Look at this
你好，安得琳娜，快看看這個
I brought the medicine for Carmelo
我給卡梅羅買了藥
Good. What is it?
好啊，什麼藥
Injections, German stuff. Don't listen to the doctor
注射的針劑，紳士用品，別聽醫生的了
The pharmacist says this is special. After a month...
藥劑師說這個是特效藥，一個月之後…
of these whoppers, Carmelo will turn into a lion!
用了這些大針劑後，卡梅羅會像雄獅一般
In a month I'll be in jail
一個月後，我就已經在監獄裡面了
Don't say that
別這麼說
"Diseases of the... para... lina... hepati..."
適用症狀：急性…加速…肝臟
What does that mean?
這是什麼意思啊
Come here. Better you than somebody else
過來吧，你肯定比某人做的好
Adelina...
安得琳娜…
I don't want to go to jail, get it? I won't go!
我不想去監獄，明白嗎，我不會去的
You keep saying you have what it takes. Show me
你總是說不論什麼都聽我的吩咐 那就現在展現給我看看
- Now?
現在
- Here?
這裡
Yes, sweetheart, but where's Carmelo?
好的，甜心，不過卡梅羅怎麼辦
At Mom's with the kids. Only the babies are here
他和孩子們在他媽媽那裡 這裡只有另外的孩子們
Come on then
過來吧
Oh my...
噢，我…
Leave off!
算了吧
Do anything you like
我願意為你做任何事情
I can't do it! I can't do it!
我不能這樣做，我不能這樣做
I want my Carmelo...
我想要我的卡梅羅…
What the hell? I don't understand you
真見鬼，你怎麼回事
Do you think I'm a clown? You wanted it and we'll do it
你覺得我是個小丑嗎 讓你召之即來揮之即去
Shame on you! Fine friend of my husband's!
不要臉的東西，我丈夫的死黨
But it was you!
可是是你先挑逗我的
Yes, it was me!
對都是我的錯
Are you crazy?
你瘋了嗎
Oh my! Poor little girls...
噢，我可憐的小寶貝…
The German stuff
給你買的男性用品
Wake up, Mommy's taking you to jail
快醒醒，媽媽帶你一起去監獄
I'm a fool to love you. I'll go to jail and that's that!
我是一個愛著你的傻瓜 正是因為這樣我就要進監獄了
We'll put an end to this farce... Goodbye
讓我們結束這場鬧劇吧…再見
Keep away, don't touch me!
滾開，別碰我
Goodbye, sissy!
再見，你這個太監
- Which one's free? - The first
- 哪裡有空位 - 一號是空的
What are you doing? She goes to the maternity section
你要幹什麼，她該到母嬰區
Why are you taking her away?
你們為什麼把她帶走
- What's your name? - Nunziatina
- 你叫什麼名字 - 紐澤阿蒂娜
Dear Nunziatina...
親愛的紐澤阿蒂娜
- Good morning, Mother - Good morning, girls
- 早上好，修女 - 早上好，姑娘們
Here's the pot
這是你的瓶瓶罐罐
- A change of baby clothes - Thank you
- 孩子的換洗衣服 - 謝謝
I know you
我見過你
You're Adelina from Forcella
你是福爾切拉的安得琳娜
- And you're Fragulella - Yes, I'm Fragulella
- 你是弗拉古萊拉 - 對啊，我是弗拉古萊拉
- And what's your name? - Assuntina
- 你叫什麼名字啊 - 阿孫蒂娜
- And you? - Pizzocca
- 你呢 - 匹索卡
- What are you in for? - Fraud
- 你為什麼進來的 - 詐騙
- What's your name? - Earthquake
- 你叫什麼名字 - 艾斯魁科
- What are you in for? - Abusing the cops!
- 你因為什麼進來的 - 侮辱警察
- And you, Fragulella? - Prostitution
- 你呢，弗拉古萊拉 - 賣淫
Aren't you going to ask me?
你不跟我說說話嗎
- What's your name? - Big Tits!
- 你叫什麼名字 - 波霸
- What are you in for? - Insulting an officer
- 你為什麼進來的 - 侮辱公務員
Well done!
幹的好
Come on, eat up. You've had nothing all day
快過來，吃點吧，你今天一天都沒吃東西了
- Are they fresh? - Sure
- 都是新鮮的嗎 - 當然啦
180 the cookies, plus the sub for Adelina's fine
180的餅乾，加上為安得琳娜償還的罰款
Hair-cut and shave, 450
剪頭髮和刮臉，450
I've always paid 350
我平時都付350
And the sub for the fine?
還有幫安得琳娜償還罰款的錢
Were you looking for me?
你在找我嗎
Cleopatra, remember the sub for the fine!
克蕾爾帕德拉，別忘了加收安得琳娜罰款金
Yes, I know
是的，我知道啦
Don't bother, I'll pay. Give me the change
別這樣，哥們，我來付吧，給我零錢
Three beers today and two orangeades yesterday
昨天的三罐啤酒和今天的兩個橙汁
- Thank you - Thank you, Sergeant!
- 謝謝 - 謝謝，警官
He's paid the sub for the fine too
他也要幫安得琳娜還罰款金
That's 40,690 lire. Do you want to count it?
這些是40690里拉，您要點點嗎
Is there any hope of collecting the full amount?
有希望全部償還嗎
40,000 lire only buys an 8-day remission of the jail term
40000里拉只夠買到8天的減刑
In a week, two weeks at most...
在一周之內，最多兩周…
I'll bring you, here 2 on this table, 300,000 lire
我會給你帶過來 這桌上的兩倍 300000里拉
and even more!
甚至更多
Are you sure?
你確定
The people of Forcella are out of this world!
福爾切拉的所有居民都行動起來了
They've risen up in a gesture of solidarity
他們都一呼百應團結一心來幫忙
It makes you forget how filthy and ignorant they are
所以你就忘了他們的骯髒和漠然
Be quiet, dear sister!
別說了，親愛的姐姐
- Sister!
修女
- What is it?
怎麼了
But it's not allowed!
但是這個是不允許的
Mind you're quiet
記住你現在還在服刑
The things you make me do!
是你讓我這麼做的
I'm sorry...
真的麻煩你了…
There she is!
她在那
Start singing! Tell her the kids are fine
快唱歌，告訴她孩子們都很好
I love her and the petition's been sent off to Rome
我愛她，請願書已經到羅馬去了
Mr Verace is expecting you
瓦斯先生已經受理了你的案件
How are you?
你好嗎
Is it true full amount has been collected?
所有款項真的已經全數湊齊了嗎
Here it is, it's even more
都已經夠了，甚至更多
This sum will buy her...
這筆現金足夠支付她
A 64-day remission of the jail term
減刑64天
The case is closed then?
那這個案件就差不多了吧
No, there's the conviction but I've applied for a pardon
不，我堅信我能申請讓她完全保釋出獄
- Your name is Verace? - Domenico Verace
- 你的名字叫做瓦斯 - 多米尼奧·瓦斯
I'm Bianchina Verace, his sister
我是比安吉娜·瓦斯，他的姐姐
I've applied to the President for a pardon, but it takes time
我已經去請求總統的特赦了 不過這需要時間
How long was she sentenced to?
她的刑期是多久
Four and a half months
四個半月
The press can do a lot to mobilize public opinion
諸位媒體們可以影響公眾輿論導向
because unless a pardon comes at once, it's no good
因為除非得到特赦 不然這個案件情況並不樂觀
I can never do right. Why aren't you pleased?
我知道我沒有錯過什麼好事 你為什麼樂觀點
- For a few days off jail? - Am I the Attorney General?
- 要離開監獄一段時間嗎 - 你以為我是誰，我是首席檢察官嗎
You're a pig, that's what!
你是頭豬，你還以為你能是什麼
The fine's paid, but who'll serve the rest of the sentence?
罰款已經都付清了，可是我卻還在這裡服刑
I hear they never grant pardons. An amnesty is different
我聽說從來沒有過特赦的例子 除非全國大赦
I have to serve the full four 1 months, but you're all right!
我不得不在這接著服刑下去 你呢，卻在外面逍遙自在
- Oh come on! - Calm down, young man
- 靠，我日 - 淡定 年輕人
You don't know what an urge I have, it's killing me!
你不知道我有多想要你，都讓我寢食難安了
I can't wait for you to get out
我等不及想讓你快出來
- I've finished the treatment! - Oh shut up!
- 我已經完成治療，完全康復了 - 你閉嘴
That's just talk! When I needed facts, you went to Mommy
就會耍嘴皮子，等到我需要你行動的時候 你就往你媽媽那裡跑
You came over dizzy!
你又突然間頭暈眼花了
Beat it! A pardon!
去你妹的，特赦
Some hope! As if they cared about me in Rome!
也許還有點希望，如果羅馬那邊能考慮的話
I don't want to see you again!
別讓我再看見你
What is it?
有什麼事嗎
Good news, Sister!
有好消息，修女
I'm here, what is it?
我在這，怎麼回事
What's happened?
發生什麼事了
You've been granted a pardon! You're free!
你已經被特赦了，你現在自由了
Oh my... I don't believe it... a pardon?
噢我…我不相信…特赦
The news came last night, but the Governor wanted to make sure
昨晚的消息，不過州長還要進一步確定
A pardon!
特赦
I've been pardoned! I'm free
我已經被特赦了，我自由了
Fragulella, I'm free! Come here...
弗拉古萊拉，我自由了，快來
I'm so happy! Don't forget us when you get out
我很高興 出去後別忘了我們
Say hello to my mother
跟我媽媽打聲招呼
Come and see me
過來，看看我
If you want to leave with the first shift, be quick!
如果你想要趕在第一批出去，就要趕快了
It's 11, there's so much to do
已經11點了，你還有好多事要做
When's Mom coming out?
媽媽什麼時候出來
You heard the lawyer, we have to wait
要聽律師的話，我們必須要等著
Will they let her out now?
他們會讓她現在出來嗎
Let's hope so
我們都希望她現在出來
Stop it!
快停下
Behave yourselves
你們好好點
or they won't let Mom out
不然他們就不讓媽媽出來了
When you go to jail, will you take me with you?
如果你去監獄了，你會帶我跟你去嗎
Mr Verace's waiting in the visitors' room, he says to hurry
瓦斯先生在探望室等著呢，他說快點
She'll be there in five minutes
她五分鐘後就到
As soon as we're all dressed!
等我們換好衣服就好了
It's 12 o'clock, will she have time to catch the first shift?
已經十二點了 她來得及趕上第一班車出來嗎
- Stop it! - There's Mom!
- 別鬧了 - 看，媽媽
Idiot, you made my heart turn over
笨蛋，別一驚一乍的
I thought it was her
我以為是她
Isn't this the best day of your life?
今天是你此生最好的一天嗎
It sure is
當然是
The news took you by surprise?
特赦的消息讓你很驚喜嗎
No, I was ready for it
沒有，我已經準備好能得到特赦
Were the kids pleased?
孩子們開心嗎
They were bursting with happiness
噢，他們已經開心爆了
Our mother's coming back!
「我們的媽媽回來了」
They were singing and dancing
他們都載歌載舞呢
I'm hungry!
我餓了
I need to piss!
我想要尿尿
They're too young to understand, poor things
他們太小了所以無法完全理解 那些悲慘的事情
How will you show your gratitude to the President?
你將會怎麼對總統表達你的感激之情
By writing him a letter, from me and my wife
我會和我的妻子給他寫一封感謝信
There's Mom!
媽媽出來了
Stop it or I'll smack you
別咋呼了，不然我就收拾你了
What can I say? I don't know anything
我該怎麼說，我不知道
Mind the streetcar! Do you want to scare me to death?
小心電車，你們想嚇死我麼
Driver, here! The car's ready
司機，這裡，車已經準備好了
Are we going by car?!
我們坐車回去
Come on children!
快過來孩子們
Guarantee pardon for only one thirthy dollars
保釋只要三分之一的美元
and the rest when the pardon comes true!
其餘的刑期因為特赦都給抵消了
No one of you wants a pardon?!
你們都不想要特赦麼
Enrico, come here
恩裡克 到這兒來
Go see who it is
去看看是誰
Who is it?
誰啊
We're going to the port, the cigarettes have come
我們要去港口，煙草到貨了
It's my first day of freedom
今天是我出獄的第一天
and this was my first night. I want to lie in
昨晚是我第一晚回來，我想躺著休息休息
Yes, stay here
恩，在家呆著吧
I'm taking the day off. See you tomorrow at the usual place
我想休息一天，明天我們老地方見吧
Don't worry, Mr Verace has promised to fix me up
別擔心，瓦斯先生保證說要引薦我
- Okay - Bye!
- 好吧 - 再見
Hurray for Mr Verace!
瓦斯先生在等著呢
Ugh, you can't move even early in the morning...
額，每個清晨都是這樣無法動彈…
What sweeties! Take it easy, fellas...
多美妙，放輕鬆，隨他去吧…
Why don't they stay home in bed, these workers?
為什麼他們不呆在家裡的床上，這些上班族
At least on Sunday morning
至少在星期天的早晨
In three days the concert. Two hours of sleep guaranteed
三天的演奏會，兩小時沉睡時間
Thank God, I'm so tired
我的天，我也太累了
Tomorrow morning, the Senator's funeral
明天早上，參議員的葬禮
I must put in an appearance
我必須要出席
At 10, the Committee meeting
十點，委員會的例會
Lunch with the in-laws
午餐要和親戚們共進
The Americans in the evening
晚上要和美國人應酬
The morning after...
早上以後…
Oh yes, Father Astolfi's orphans
噢，對了，阿斯托爾非神父的孤兒們
Then the hairdresser's
然後是髮型師
Look in at Titti's, 1 then an hour's workout
之後去翠兒那探望一下 然後一個小時的鍛煉時間
Then back to the hairdresser's
然後回到髮型師那裡去
Then look in at Titti's again
然後再去一趟翠兒那
Then the prize-giving of those wretched orphans
再然後給那些不幸的孤兒們發放獎金
Enough, enough! Away! A clean break
夠了，夠了，走開，讓我休息下
Definitively
真是的
Renzo, I can't remember the color of your eyes right now
倫索，我現在已經記不清你眼睛的顏色了
The darling, with that serious face. He's the best man I know
親愛的你，那張嚴肅的臉龐 他是我所知道的最棒的男人了
So generous, so free so unassuming
如此的英俊，如此獨立卻如此謙遜
The darling, with those incredible short socks!
親愛的你，卻穿著如此令人意外的短襪
There he is
他在那
- Am I late? - No, I just got here
- 我來晚了嗎 - 沒有，我也剛剛到
- Where shall we go? - No idea. You decide
- 我們去哪裡 - 不知道，你決定吧
It's hot in here. Mind if I open it up?
這兒好熱，你不介意我打開它吧
Of course not
當然不介意
Were you surprised I called?
接到我的電話你驚訝嗎
No, I was expecting it
不，這是我意料之中的
I'd have called if you hadn't
即使你不給我打電話，我也會給你打的
If you've time, how about a drive?
如果你有空的話，就一直開下去怎麼樣
I have all the time you want
我所有的時間都是為你而準備的
- Is that your husband? - Yes
- 那是你丈夫的嗎 - 是的
Where is he now?
他現在在哪
In Stuttgart, for the EEC. He'll be away another week
在斯圖加特參與歐洲經濟共同體會議 他下周也不在
How does it feel, seeing your name everywhere?
你有什麼感覺 當看到到處都是你的名字的時候
I don't even notice any more
我已經不去在意它了
Besides, my name is Anna, remember?
另外，我的名字叫安娜，你還記得嗎
You've changed since last night, you hardly know me
你昨晚之後就有點變了 你已經不能瞭解我了嗎
It's just that seeing you arrive took my breath away
當我看到你開車到我身邊的那一瞬間 我的呼吸都暫停了呢
Classy, huh?
高級貨，嗯
After you took me home last night, I couldn't sleep
你昨晚把我送回家之後 我就難以入睡
The things you said to me... I've never felt so unhappy
你跟我說過的話，我從未感到這樣的不安
- Why? - Because you're right
- 為什麼 - 因為你說的對
I've lived like a puppet, deaf, blind, oblivious...
我活像一個傀儡，聾子，瞎子，輕易忘卻
to the rights of others
其他的美好的存在
I realized that while I was dancing with you
當我和你跳舞的時候，我意識到
I felt alive for the first time, in your arms
在你的懷中的時候 我第一次感覺到自己是活著的
What's the world coming to!
這個世界怎麼了
Let's close the roof
讓我們把敞篷蓋上吧
Scared someone will see you?
害怕有人看到嗎
I said it for your sake. It could happen
我說過是因為你的緣故 所以一切才發生的
If you're worried about my husband, relax
如果是擔心我丈夫的緣故，那就放輕鬆
It sounds as if you mind
聽起來似乎你有所芥蒂
Nobody likes living with an addict
沒有人願意和一個癮君子生活在一起
I didn't know
我不知道這件事
Yes, an addict. Not in the way you think, but it's worse
是的，一個癮君子 不是你想像的那樣，不過仍然很糟糕
He's part of the system: work, success, money
他是大系統的一部分，工作，成功，金錢
Money, success, work
金錢，成功，工作
You can't stop him
你無法讓他停止
And nothing else exists
也沒有什麼能讓他走出來
And are you different?
那你們有什麼不同嗎
Yes, you made me realize that. Thank you, Renzo
對啊，你讓我意識到了這件事，謝謝，倫索
I think I talked a lot of nonsense last night
我覺得我昨晚說了一大堆廢話
Why, what's changed?
為什麼，有什麼有所改變嗎
How many millions do you have?
你有幾百萬財富
What does that have to do with it?
有什麼意義嗎
- A lot - You're being mean
- 很大意義 - 你別在這兒另有所指
Slow down!
慢點開
Would you like to drive? Go on!
你想要開一下嗎，來吧
No, I don't know these cars. My limit is a Fiat 600
不，我不太會開這種高檔車 我頂多開菲亞特600
But this one's easy
不過這台很好開的
- No, better not - Come on, change over
- 不，最好不要 - 快來，換換吧
It's perfect, you'll see. Does 120 like nothing
它很棒，你開的時候就發現 120就像什麼都沒發生一樣
And it's just been serviced
而且，它，剛剛保養過
The key's there
鑰匙在這
Where's the indicator? Ah, here it is
指示燈在哪，噢，在這兒呢
A bit of music?
來點音樂吧
Well, Renzo?
倫索
Anna, I like you a lot
安娜，我非常喜歡你
But you don't think I'm sincere
可是，你並不認為我是真誠的
I don't know... I don't know
我不知道…我不知道
Look, we're low on gas
看，我們已經快沒油了
That's the heat. I filled up this morning
那個是暖氣，我今天早上才加的油
- How much does it hold? - 20 gallons, I guess
- 這車能加多少油 - 20加侖，我猜
Enough to take mine around the world
足夠讓我的車環遊世界了
Do you like traveling too?
你也喜歡旅行
The minute I can, I go far away from everything
現在我也想要旅行 我要把所有的事情拋在腦後走得遠遠的
I'm so tired of my world, the people I know
我對於我的世界和我認識的人已經厭倦了
There's an oasis near Marrakesh, it's divine!
在馬拉喀什有片綠洲，我們往那開吧
You live on sun and fruit, lots of fruit
你會沐浴在陽光下蔬果香中生活 好多好多的水果
- 1,200,000 - What?
- 1200000 - 什麼
The return fare
往返費用
- Oh, Renzo, stop it! - It's the truth
- 倫索，快別說了 - 這是事實
The truth is you keep turning the conversation to money!
事實是你把這個話題轉到錢上去了
You know what I make a month?
你知道我一個月能掙多少嗎
I don't want to know! Don't you understand?
我不想知道，你難道不明白嗎
I like you because you're not like the robots I know
我喜歡你正是因為你 和我認識的那些機器人是不一樣的
busy making money all day
那些整天忙著掙錢的
You write, you're intelligent. I never think about money
你寫過說，你是聰慧過人的 我從來沒有想過錢的事
- I swear I don't - Because you have it
- 我發誓我沒有 - 但是因為你擁有它
So, should I throw it away?
所以，難道我應該把它都丟掉嗎
Yes, everything: money, cars, those Cleopatra bracelets
是的，所以東西，錢、車、還有克麗奧佩托拉手鐲 （克麗奧佩托拉是埃及女皇七世，即我們熟知的埃及艷後）
I got these at the hardware store
我是在五金店買到它的
Did you get this monument at the hardware store too?
你也去五金店買這種古玩
But that's not it. The fact is you have money in you
不過，這不是我的意思，事實是你很富有
In me there's only emptiness... a big emptiness
對我而言這兒只有空虛…大大的空虛
I thought you could have helped me
我覺得你必須要幫幫我
Where do you want to go?
你到底要到哪去
We could go to my place
我們可以去我住的地方
My villa's near here. There's a lake too
我的別墅就在這附近，那裡也有一個湖
- How big is the lake? - Small
- 多大的湖 - 很小的湖
My husband had it made to fish trout
我丈夫用它來養鱒魚
- We'll go to the River Po - Lovely! What is there?
- 我們去波河吧 - 好啊，那裡有什麼
Mosquitoes, one thing your husband didn't make
蚊子，你丈夫唯一無法賺取的東西
Sorry...
對不起…
Let's go anywhere, wherever you like
只要你喜歡去哪都行
As long as there's a bit of peace and quiet
只要有安靜平和的地方都行
There, look! That's fine
那兒，看，那邊不錯呢
How wonderful!
風景真好啊
"Our jazz program continues..."
我們的爵士專題繼續播出…
In a few days this lovely October will be over too
再過幾天宜人的十月份也要過去了
Not here, please. Let's go away
別在這兒了，我們走吧
God!
天吶
You like me, I can tell
我得說，你是喜歡我的
If you hadn't called me, who would you have called?
如果你沒有打電話給我今天 你會打電話給誰
Nobody... I'm alone
沒人…我很孤獨
With all the people you know?
包括你認識的那些人
With all the people I know
包括我認識的那些人
I can't tell which are your fingers and which are mine
我們十指交扣無法分離
This is so lovely, unbelievable...
這是如此美好，難以言語的美好
Help me
救救我
Let's go far away, to the sun. To Rome, Naples
讓我們走得遠遠的 去陽光下，去羅馬納普勒斯
Yes, let's go
走吧，我們走
We'll arrive at night, in the lamplight
等到晚上我們就會在燈光下到達
The still, silky water...
那平靜的，如絲光般順滑的池水…
We'll ride in a trap and find a nice small place, just for us
我們會駕駛馬車找到一個溫馨的小旅館 只有你和我
The dark sky full of stars...
漆黑的夜空佈滿星辰…
And music, lots of music in the air
還有音樂，音樂從空中飄來
under our windows
在我們的窗下迴響
Tomorrow we'll wake up late, as the sun creeps onto the bed...
明天我們會遲遲起床 正如陽光緩慢灑到床上…
You'll take me in your arms, you'll hold me tight...
你會把我摟在懷裡，緊緊的把我摟在懷裡
- Anna, are you hurt? - No, it's nothing
- 安娜，受傷了嗎 - 沒，我沒事
We're on fire!
我們著火了
The car!
這個車
My God, what have you done?
我的天那，你做了什麼好事
I had to put the brakes on...
我不得不撞向...
Something's burning!
什麼東西起火了
The tire's burning!
輪胎起火了
Do something, you fool! The car's on fire!
快點行動，你這個蠢貨，車起火了
Find something to put it out!
快找點東西蓋上去滅火
How could anybody be so dumb!
怎麼會有人像你這麼蠢
Are you crazy, with my fur? Use your jacket!
你瘋了嗎，用我的皮草大衣 用你自己的夾克外套
God, the whole thing's going to blow up. Get the jack!
天那，全都要著火了，快去拿千斤頂
- What are you doing? - I can't open it!
- 你在幹什麼 - 我打不開它
Jesus Christ!
上帝耶穌啊
The jack! Surely you know what a jack is!
千斤頂，你知不知道什麼是千斤頂啊
You must have rammed on the brakes like a brute
你肯定撞它像宰殺牲口一樣
These cars are delicate, they're jewels!
這輛車是精美而嬌弱的，它是珠寶
And you stamp on the brake like it was a truck!
你肯定踩剎車像踩一頭牲口一樣
- But I could have killed him! - Who cares!
- 我會把他殺了 - 那又怎樣
Now what are you doing?
現在你又要幹什麼
Would you mind giving me a hand? I'm in trouble
您介意幫我個忙嗎，我現在有點小麻煩
I think it's serious
我覺得情況比較嚴重
If I can be of any help. What's wrong?
如果我能幫得上忙，我樂意效勞 發生什麼事了
I don't know, please come and take a look
我不知道，請帶我去看一看
We were speeding and we suddenly had to brake hard to swerve
我們正在行駛，突然間掉頭 就發生了相撞事故
It's jammed, I don't know what to do
就被卡住了，我不知道該怎麼辦才好
- It's a Rolls - Yes, the latest model
- 這是勞斯萊斯啊 - 是最新款
- Are you happy with it? - Yes, no problem until now
- 開起來感覺不錯吧 - 的確不錯，直到剛才
That's quite a bump. Were you driving?
撞得不輕啊，是你駕駛的嗎
It was all so sudden. The car swerved and went off the road
就是突然間，轎車急轉彎就在路上熄火了
Strange, these cars are perfect
怎奇怪，這種車型 在各方面都是應該是完美的
I was a fool to let a Fiat-600 driver handle it
我太蠢了，讓一個只能開 菲亞特600的司機來開這種好車
- A colossal mistake - You're quite right
- 真是一個大錯誤 - 你說的太對了
- Would you like me to help? - Goodness no
- 你需要我幫忙做點什麼麼 - 無須勞駕您，女士
You see, these cars with the rim-braking system...
你看，這種車都是鋼圈制動機系統…
I prefer disc brakes, they're better
我還是喜歡盤式制動機，那種更容易駕駛
It's not the brakes, it's knowing how to drive the car
不是制動機的問題 是駕駛員的駕駛常識的問題
Even the Divine Comedy in illiterate hands...
就像流傳千古的喜劇故事 不會是一個文盲寫出來的…
Let's hope for the best
只能往好的地方想想了
Don't worry, the damage can easily be fixed
別擔心，這個損傷很容易修理的
Haven't we met before?
我們之前見過面嗎
You look familiar too
我也覺得你看起來很面熟
I guess we met in Casorate, with my husband, at the Martin's
我猜好像是在卡索拉太普 我和我的丈夫，我們在馬丁那裡見過
Is your husband in Milan?
你的丈夫在米蘭嗎
No, he's in Stuttgart on EEC business
沒有，他在斯圖亞特忙著 歐洲經濟共同體會議的事
He'll be away a week. Thank God, with this disaster
他這一周都不在，謝天謝地，他不在場
You'd better call a mechanic
你最好還是叫修配師來吧
Definitely, that one is absolutely hopeless
當然啦，他們是最後一絲希望了
I can turn around and drive you home
我可以掉轉車頭，把你送回家
- I'm Giorgio Carate - Pleased to meet you
- 我叫喬治·卡拉特 - 見到你很高興
I'm going home. This gentleman's taking me
我要回家了，這位紳士要送我回家
We'll send a mechanic
我們會叫修配師來修車的
Keep an eye on it, do me a favor. Thanks!
幫幫忙，幫我看著這輛車吧，謝謝
"Milan Stock Exchange rates"
米蘭股市交易所兌換的指數
"Molini Certosa 2700"
莫特尼·賽特薩，2700
"Distillati 2490"
蒂斯帝拉蒂，2490
"Eridania 2603..."
埃利達尼亞糖業，2603
Is this a Rools Royce?
這真的是勞斯萊斯
Does it really do 150?
這真的能跑到150
More than a Ferrari!
比法拉第還快
What do you want?
你想要幹什麼
100 lire
100里拉
Hello? Yes, I was in the bathroom
哪位，是我，我剛在泡澡
No, I can't today... Sorry, I'm busy...
今天不行，對不起，我今天很忙
Mind where you put your feet, you'll scare them!
注意腳下，你把它們都嚇跑了
Oh, the Bolognese! Come in
博洛尼亞，快請進
Darling! Sweetheart!
親愛的，甜心
You beautiful doll, you look wonderful!
你這個美麗的洋娃娃，惹人愛憐的小可愛
Ouiet, don't shout!
小點聲，別大吵大鬧的
- Come in the other room - I can't. Later
- 快點進屋去吧 - 我一刻也等不下去了
I have a few things for you. I just wanted to see you
我給你帶了些小禮物，我就是想要見見你
To kiss you, to touch you...
親吻，愛撫你
Mara, wait! Listen, I have to go to the Ministry
瑪拉，等等，聽著，我必須要去政府
You queen! You empress!
你是女王，你是我的女皇殿下
When I'm in love, I sweat!
當我墜入愛河的時候，我總是流汗
Use and discard...
用過就丟掉…
They're very practical
它們非常實用
Wait for me tonight. Make me die, I'm counting on it!
今晚等我，讓我飄飄欲仙 我都已經迫不及待了
Think of me, Bolognese
替想想我吧，博洛尼亞
- What's got into you? - I want to die there!
- 你到底怎麼了 - 我就是要在這裡飄飄欲仙
Now I've got to be strong, I've got to resist!
我現在力大無窮，我要你欲拒還迎
- How can I resist? - Don't shout!
- 我該怎麼欲拒還迎 - 別大吵大鬧
Wear this tonight
今晚穿上這個
I want you to dress like a little girl
我想要你穿成一個小女孩的樣子
Are you crazy?
你瘋了嗎
You can call me uncle
你可以叫我叔叔
You're nuts, you Bolognese. Do you get a kick out of it?
你傻了吧，我的博洛尼亞 你怎麼開始癡迷角色扮演了
I need a lot of tenderness, Mara
我需要你的慰藉，瑪拉
Next time I'll wear short pants
下次我會穿短褲的
You'll sing me a lullaby and I'll fall asleep in your arms
你會為我唱搖籃曲 而我會在你的懷中甜甜的睡去
Now I'll hurry to the Ministry or my father will kill me
我要趕快去政府了，不然我爸爸會殺了我
May I call him?
我能給他在這打個電話嗎
Bologna, Miss, very urgent! Bologna 543221
博洛尼亞小姐請趕快給我 接通博洛尼亞，543221
This is 577000
這裡是577000
Jesus, it's easy! 5-7-7 and three zeroes. Six numbers
上帝，多好記的號碼 5-7-7 然後是三個0，一共是六位數
It'll take her till Christmas
等到聖誕節她才能接通吧
I'll stay here tonight...
我今晚要整晚呆在這
Hello? Yes, Dad, it's me
爸爸，是我
Yes, I went
是的，我去了
No, the permit's not ready
沒有，現在還沒有拿到許可證
Yes, I went to see the Under Secretary
是的，我去見過副部長了
You'll see, I'll settle it tonight. It only needs stamping
你放心，今天一定會全部解決的 接下來就只是需要蓋章而已拉
But I'm not an idiot!
我不是個傻瓜
I won't let you go!
我不會讓你走的
Look at you, there isn't one thing wrong with you
你看起來是那麼完美
Make a face or I can't go
做個鬼臉吧，不然我就走不了了
No, don't make faces, it turns me on even more!
別做鬼臉，做鬼臉讓我更無法自拔
Where's your college?
你在哪讀書
At Anagni, but the head-office is in Lombardy.
在安那尼，不過總部在倫巴第
- How many hours do you study? - 12
- 你每天學習多久 - 十二小時
My-oh-my!
我的天
Five hours of meditation and prayer, seven of study
五小時祈禱和冥想，七小時的時間學習
When do you get time off?
那什麼時候休息
Recreation after lunch, and an hour in the evening
午餐後有一小時的休閒時間 晚上也有一小時
My nephew's with the friars. They say the rosary at midnight
我的侄子也在跟隨修道士學習 他們在午夜時分就誦讀玫瑰經
The Capuchins have that rule
聖方濟會托缽僧的規矩
No, thank you
不，謝謝
Aren't you allowed to? I saw a bishop with a pipe once
你不抽，我見過一個主教在抽煙斗
It's forbidden at college
在學校這是被禁止的
You give me the urge to come to confession
你讓我有想要懺悔的想法
in this lovely moonlight
在這個寧靜的夜晚
I couldn't hear it, I'm not a priest yet
我現在還不能聽你的懺悔 我現在還不是一個神父
I take my vows in two years
我還要再過兩年宣誓以後才可以
You're dressed like a priest
可是你已經穿著神父的衣服了
But I'm not
不過我還不是神父
I love black, I wear it on top and underneath...
我喜歡黑色，我總是穿黑色的上衣和內衣…
When the Council's over, will priests be allowed... to marry?
當教會結束的時候 神父們會被允許…結婚嗎
I don't think so
我覺得不會
American priests have children
美國的神父都是有孩子的
But I don't like that
可是我不喜歡那樣
Priests should be like the moon:
不過神父大多喜歡月亮
nobody knows what it is
沒有人能解釋清楚原因
They're men with a religious vocation
他們是因為宗教信仰的原因吧
My nephew's vocation was beaten into him by his mother!
我侄子的媽媽總是灌輸他這樣的想法
You like it?
你喜歡這樣
Yes, but I'm free decide for myself
是的，我可以自己做主
There's plenty of time before my vows. I'll pray to my saint
在你宣誓之前你還有很多時間呢 我會向我的聖人禱告
- Who's that? - Saint John
- 你的聖人是誰 - 聖約翰
I have one nobody knows. Saint Maurillo
我有一個沒人聽說過的聖人 聖毛裡洛
- Do you know him? - No
- 你聽說過他嗎 - 沒有
I need one who doesn't get pestered, who has time for me
我的聖人是沒有別人打擾 有足夠時間陪我的聖人
I ask him to let me make lots of money
我向他請求過讓我掙很多很多錢
- Does he answer you? - Pretty well
- 他回應你了嗎 - 回應了我很多很多
But... I don't like my job
不過，我並不喜歡我的工作
- What do you do? - Manicurist
- 你的工作是什麼 - 指甲修剪師
But I pick my clients, respectable people who pay well
不過我很挑剔客戶 只挑那些慷慨大方舉止體面的客人
I want to buy my father some land
我想要給我父親買一塊地
The hands I've seen! I can judge people by them
我通過不同客人的手來評斷客人
Let me see yours
讓我看看你的手吧
You're level-headed and you like sport
你是一個沉著冷靜的人，而且喜歡運動
I used to playinside right...
我曾經玩過一段時間的體育運動…
There's a great destiny here
你有一個光明的前途
- I can tell you're kind - How can you tell?
- 你真好 - 你怎麼知道
By everything
無論從哪方面都能看出來
You're predestined! My, how straight that line is!
你注定如此，紋路好直
You can ask anything of life
你可咨問任何有關生活的事情
I'd like to go out with you
我明天想要和你去散步
Yes, arm-in-arm!
是啊，肩並肩的散步
Think of the neighbors, think of your grandmother!
想想這些鄰居吧，想想你的祖母
And dressed like a priest!
而且你還穿得像個神父
But I have a suit. It's a bit old...
我有其他的西裝，就是有點舊而已
We'll go to the sea
我會去海邊吧
I'd like that, now that it's not so crowded
我喜歡海邊散步 而且現在也沒有那麼多遊客
We'll stay there all day, I'll bring some sandwiches
我們可以在那呆一整天 我會帶些三明治去的
We'll see... we'll see
那我們明天見吧
Oh pussy! Come here...
貓貓，快過來
I ought to leave tomorrow, but I can be a day late
我本應該明天離開 不過我為了你我願意多呆一天
When will you be back?
你什麼時候回來
At Christmas, to see my grandparents
聖誕節的時候，回來看我的外公外婆
I'll think it over tonight about going to the sea
我覺得明天還是別去海邊了
I wonder who he belongs to? He often comes to see me
我想知道誰是他的主人，他經常來這裡看我
It was so nice here
他很可愛很溫順
I'll wait for you
我會在這裡等你
This one will be here for some time
這個是常客
He's come from Bologna on business
他是從普拉尼亞來的生意人
I'll wait here until dawn
我會在這裡一直等著直到你忙完
Take the cat
貓貓給你吧
- Bye! - Good night
- 再見 - 晚安
Why aren't you in bed yet?
為什麼你現在還不睡覺
I'm going, Gran! Excuse me...
我就去，奶奶，對不起，麻煩你
- Good evening, ma'am - I don't know you
- 晚上好 夫人 - 我不認識你
You know me now
那你現在認識我了
I don't know you, nor does my grandson
不僅我不認識你，我的孫子也不認識
Umberto, go to bed!
翁貝托，快去睡覺
Good night, Miss
晚安，小姐
I'll have a wall built here
我會在這裡壘一道牆
Thank goodness he's leaving tomorrow
謝天謝地，他明天就要走了
I won't leave unless you apologize to the young lady!
我不會走的，除非你向這位年輕的小姐道歉
Over my dead body!
那就等我死了吧
- I'm sorry, Miss - Don't mention it
- 對不起，小姐 - 別介意
Leave the boy alone
讓這個孩子一個人清淨清淨
He's not like the men who come to your house
他和那些到你住處的男人不是一種人
This boy's a saint!
他還是一個聖徒
Only respectable people come to my house!
來我住處的都是有身份的人
The one at the door now is Cavaliere Rusconi's son!
現在在門口的 就是卡瓦裡耶爾·拉斯科尼的兒子
A fine thing!
聽起來不錯啊
Government deputies come to my house too!
政府指定他們來我這裡的
And Tommasi, the pasta producer
還有托馬斯，那個意大利面生產商
I see you eat Tommasi pasta
我看到連你們吃的都是托馬斯牌的意大利面
I won't any more
我以後再也不會吃這個牌子了
Tomorrow I'll send a petition around, everybody will sign it
明天我會向所有人發請願書 每個人都會在上面簽字
You'll leave the building. We're tired of this coming and going
你會被趕出這個大樓 我們已經厭煩了 看到你這裡客來客往的
You're a scandal. Yesterday I counted four men!
你是我們住戶中的醜聞 昨天我就看到了四個男人來你這裡
Do you want to put a meter on me?
你要窺探我的生活嗎
Three yes and four no? My client are quiet, well-behaved people
計算著是三個，不是四個 我的客人都很安靜而富有涵養
You'll go to hell, mark my words. Shame on you, I'll report you!
你是會下地獄的，你給我記著 你這個臭不要臉的，我會去舉報你
Stop it, Gran! You're an old goose!
別說了，奶奶，你這個愚蠢的老婦
You... old... witch! What does she want from me?
老巫婆，她到底想要我怎麼樣
Vincenzo! Come away!
文森佐，快進來
Her and that other old goat!
她和她的一切都去死吧
She'll report me, she'll send me to hell. Jesus!
她要舉報我，她要我下地獄 上帝啊
Listen to this one
聽聽這個
All right! All right! I heard you!
別按了，我聽到你了
At last! I was starting to worry
剛剛我都開始不放心你了
Why ring like that?
為什麼按門鈴按得這麼粗魯
- Gorgeous! - Oh come in
- 美人 - 快來
I thought there'd been a gas leak
我還以為你的煤氣洩露了呢
Pussy... Is he new?
貓貓，他是新寵嗎
I'll show that old witch. I'll fix that boy, you'll see!
我會給老巫婆點顏色看看的 我會好好修理那個男孩，你就看著吧
What boy? What old witch?
什麼男孩，什麼老巫婆
Next-door. She hates me talking to her grandson!
隔壁的，她討厭我和她孫子搭訕
It's crazy! As if I'd go with a priest!
太瘋狂了 好像我真的要和一個神父約會一樣
He isn't even 18
他還不滿18歲
We're talking about God and she yells I'll go to hell
我們在討論上帝的事 她就開始對我大吵大鬧讓我下地獄去
She's given me a headache
她真讓我頭疼
Take no notice of her: do no evil, fear no evil
別理她，別在乎那些魔鬼，別害怕那些魔鬼
She says she'll tell my landlady
她說她要和我的房東談談
Landladies are sympathetic, they just put the rent up
房東不會說什麼的，他們要的只是房租
I know, as if I didn't pay enough!
我知道，就好像我沒有交夠錢一樣
But I'll make Granny sorry!
不過我會讓這個奶奶後悔的
You have to understand
你必須明白
Come here, come to Uncle
過來，來叔叔這裡
As if I felt like making love!
就像我們要做愛一樣
Come on, Mara. We'll go to bed and cuddle up together
來吧瑪拉，我們去床上親熱親熱吧
Like good children. We won't even talk
像個乖寶寶那樣，我們都不需要語言交流的
- I need to talk! - Okay, but in bed
- 我需要交流 - 好吧好吧，不過在床上好不好
I'm too mad, I'd be like a stone
我太生氣了, 簡直就是被人當頭棒喝
Be honest, am I a scandal? Do I do it on the terrace?
不過說真的，我真的是一個醜聞嗎 我難道在陽台上做了嗎
I'm willing to go out on the terrace.
我想要和你在陽台上做
Like Nero looking at Rome
像尼奧在羅馬的時候那樣
Don't I always ask everybody... not to shout?
別總是在意別人的眼光
To talk quietly? When you yell you sound like a donkey
難道要忍氣吞聲嗎 當你大嚷的時候 你的聲音聽起來就像一頭蠢驢
Because I'm different
這正是我與眾不同之處
I love you, I think you're perfect. Do you love me?
我愛你，在我眼裡你是完美的 你難道不愛我嗎
- Here... - I love you
- 拿著 - 我愛你
- Let's run away together - Who's chasing us?
- 讓我們遠走高飛吧 - 有誰在追趕我們嗎
I don't like you going with other men, I'm jealous
我不喜歡你和其他男人在一起，我嫉妒他們
Marry me then
那就跟我結婚
What for? Why don't you come to Bologna for a month?
為什麼要結婚 為什麼不去博洛尼亞呆一個月
I won't budge from here. The old witch would love that
我不會離開這裡半步 那個老巫婆不會得逞的
In fact I'll buy this apartment she'll be stuck with me forever
而且，我會把這裡買下來 她永遠都別想躲開我
Let's do it here, it would be heavenly
讓我們在這做吧，一定會很美妙的
We'll turn the lights out and open the refrigerator
我們把燈都給關了，然後把冰箱打開
Look what a nice cosy light
看，多麼溫馨的燈光
I'll write her a letter, I want to let off steam
我會給她寫封信，我要讓她發瘋
I saw a terrific show in Paris
我在巴黎看過一個漆黑的表演
Black striptease! We need music
黑暗中的脫衣舞，我們需要點音樂
This is scented. I'm not sending her scented paper
這張紙有香味 我不會用有香味的信紙給她寫信的
- Let's turn the lights out - I've got to write
- 讓我們把燈關了吧 - 我正要寫東西呢
Just for a minute
就一會兒
Will you correct if for me?
你會不會幫我修改這封信
I don't want her to find any mistakes
我不想讓她發現我任何書寫的瑕疵
Sure
當然沒問題
The woman's shapely leg slowly comes into the light...
那些女人的美腿慢慢的從燈光中顯現出來
What's he up to?
他怎麼回事
The light creeps up slowly...
燈光緩緩的輕柔的
very very slowly...
非常非常輕柔的
It takes your breath away. I was really turned on...
這都快要讓人窒息了，我都快要慾火焚身了
They have time to waste!
他們卻還在浪費時間
Turn the light on!
把燈打開
Umberto!
博蘭尼亞
You won't see me again! You treat me like a doormat!
你再也不會見到我了 你竟然像對待下等人一樣對待我
You're not the only woman around, I can find any number
你不是世界上唯一的女人 我可以找到任何的女人
Sit down and be good
坐下來，好好呆著
You think I'm a slave to sex
你以為我是性的奴隸嗎
but I have a soul too, remember that
我也是有靈魂的，你給我記住了
Look, there's only a hair between a devil and a saint!
魔鬼和天使也只有一線之隔
My life's about to change. I'm going home to find a wife
我的生活不會再這樣了 我會回家娶妻生子的
Sure, you must get married
當然了，你必須要結婚
Dear Madam...
親愛的夫人
"Dear"?!
親愛的
My father may call,
我父親也許會打電話過來
I left him your number in case it was urgent
我把你的電話留給他了，為了以備不時之需
Fake a man's voice and say I'm out
裝出男人的聲音告訴他我走了就好了
Goodbye
再見
I said I'm sorry. Do you want to hit me over the head?
我要說，對不起，起來
This isn't a hotel, you know. Get up, I have to go shopping
這是個旅館，你知道，起來，我要去逛街了
Mara, last night I came to Piazza Navona
瑪拉，我昨晚去了納沃納廣場
I sat on a bench and looked up at your window
我坐在長椅上面抬頭看著你的窗戶
Then I couldn't hold out any longer and I went with a...
然後我就再也沒辦法把持自己，所以我去了
- Whore - Yes
- 妓院 - 是的
Can't you miss even one day?
你一天不做都不行是麼
We didn't do anything, I swear
我們什麼也沒做，我發誓
and I shouted to her, go away!
我突然覺得有什麼不對 然後我就朝她吼滾開
- She started insulting me - She was right
- 她就開始辱罵我 - 她是對的
But I paid her anyway!
可是我有付錢
They have their self-respect too, you have to understand
她們也有自己的反應啊，你必須要理解
Come on, get up
過來，起來吧
Thank you
謝謝
Couldn't you put a carpet down here?
你不能在這裡鋪個地毯嗎
A soft red runner... I'll buy one for you
一條小小的紅毯，我會給你買一個的
Listen, I have an hour before I see the Under Secretary
聽著，我只有一個小時的時間 然後我要去見副部長
We've never been together in the morning
我們早上從來沒有在一起過
Just for an hour, okay?
只要一個小時，行嗎
Oh all right
來吧
- Don't undo it! - Ouiet, the old witch will hear!
- 別脫下 - 小點聲，那個老巫婆能聽見
You give me a bad name
你會讓我名聲不好的
- I want to undress you - Be quiet!
- 我想要給你脫衣服 - 小點聲
You're a vision! You know what I'd like?
你真是一道美景，你知道我喜歡什麼嗎
To see you in a fur coat, nude, in the sunshine
喜歡看著在陽光下裸體穿著皮草大衣
Are you nuts, in this heat?
你傻了吧，難道不熱嗎
Hello? Oh, Vani from Venice!
威尼斯的瓦尼
Sure I remember. Short, with a moustache. The bass player
當然啦，我記得你 小個子，有鬍子是個貝司手
You're the bass player, right? I remember
你是個貝司手吧，對吧，我記得呢
Try tomorrow. Sure I'll give you a grade, I promised
明天嗎，好啊，我會好好伺候你的，我保證
Come on, you beautiful doll
過來，你這個漂亮的洋娃娃
I'll set my family against the old witch, there's seven of us
我會讓我的家人一起來對抗這個老巫婆 我們七個人一起
Eight with me, darling
我們八個，親愛的
- Are you going to be all day? - It's hard and I'm shaking
- 你打算這樣解扣子一整天嗎 - 這個很難解而且我在顫抖呢
Let me see if they're up
讓我去看看把它關了
Hey, look at that!
快看
He's taken his cassock off. The old witch will be furious
他把他的修道服給脫了 那個老巫婆一定暴跳如雷
The boy's got character. Come and look
這孩子真有性格，快來看
Well done!
幹得好
Hi!
嗨
I'll shoot him!
讓我去揍他
Please, it turns me off if you laugh. This is serious
求你了，你一笑讓我一點慾望都沒有了 這是一件很嚴肅的事情
The best thing in the world
這是這世界最美妙的事
- You're not in! - I'll take a peep
- 假裝你不在 - 我去看看是誰
- It's Gran! - Don't open it!
- 是那個奶奶 - 別開門
She looks out of her mind!
她看起來不太對勁
I'll go
我去看看
- Who is it? - Open the door!
- 是誰啊 - 把門打開
- But who is it? - Giovanna Villenzone
- 到底是誰 - 喬萬娜·未蘭佐尼
- Never heard of her - Umberto's grandmother
- 從未聽說過這個人 - 翁貝托的奶奶
Well?
有什麼事嗎
I want to speak to you... just for a minute
我想要和你談談，就只要一小會兒
I must speak to you
我必須要和你談談
It's too early for visitors
這個時間來拜訪有點太早了吧
Come in, ma'am
快進來吧，夫人
What is it?
發生什麼事了
- It's all over! - Don't cry
- 一切都完了 - 別哭
You've ruined me, you've ruined my family
你把我毀了，你把我的家庭毀了
If you stop crying we can put everything right
如果您先別哭 我們會把一切問題都解決好的
Please stop crying, ma'am.
請別哭了，夫人
He was an angel, respectful, obedient, and he's lost his head
他是一個天使，受人尊敬的，聽話的 可是他現在已經迷失了自我
Calm down, we'll fix it
冷靜些，我們會解決它的
It's too late. He's put brilliantine on his hair
太晚了，他已經在自己的頭上塗滿了潤發油
He took his cassock off... it's time to put a stop on it!
而且還脫掉了修道服，應該趕快制止他
...where's the window?!?
窗戶在哪裡
Please calm down, ma'am
請冷靜，女士
Calm down
冷靜
- Mr Rusconi - Pleased to meet you
- 博蘭尼亞先生 - 見到你很高興
Do you know Umberto studied all the time?
你知道翁貝托以前是那麼的勤奮好學
He even read at night. You know he could have become Pope?
他徹夜苦讀，你知道他是可以成為教宗的
He will, he will
他會的，他會的
Come into the parlor, ma'am
請到客廳來，夫人
- Thank you - Don't mention it
- 謝謝 - 不用客氣
Give the lady a Fernet
給這位女士一杯弗拉卡
Or would you prefer something sweet?
還是您喜歡吃點糖果
I have Strega, aniseed... whatever you like
我還有斯德拉酒，茴香酒…您想喝點什麼
He refuses to go back to the seminary
他還拒絕回到學校去
We'll make him go back, I'll see to it
我們要一起去送他，我會看著他
He says you're a saint and I'm a witch
他還說你是一個聖女，而我是一個巫婆
You can go now, Rusconi. Granny's feeling better
你現在可以走了，博洛尼亞 奶奶已經覺得好多了
Wait for me in the other room. Use the phone if you like
在別的房間裡等我吧 你也可以給你爸爸打個電話
- Did I disturb you? - No
- 我打擾你們了嗎 - 沒有
The gentleman's very kind. He's from Emilia
這位紳士人非常好，他是從艾米麗亞來的
- I have relations there - That's nice
- 我在那裡有親戚 - 那真不錯
Listen, you may tell your grandson whatever you like
聽著，你可以跟你孫子把事情都說了
By all means tell him the truth
把真相都告訴他
I have, but he doesn't believe me
我已經說了，可是他不相信我
- Keep trying - Thank you. Umberto's parents
- 再試試 - 謝謝，翁貝托的父母
have such great hopes in him. My daughter has a weak heart.
對他抱有很大的期望 我女兒有心臟病
You know what a son means
你也知道一個兒子對她意味著什麼
- But I want a son too - Good girl
- 對啊我也想要個兒子 - 真是好姑娘
First I have to put some money by, for his security
首先我要為此準備一筆錢 為了他的將來著想
You know what? I'll make a vow, they always work for me
你知道嗎，我發誓過，讓他們都為我而工作
If Umberto goes back to the seminary, I'll go a week without
如果翁貝托回到學校繼續學習 我會停止一周
You know what
你知道，那個
That's very generous of you
你真是太慷慨了
A week! And when I say something, I mean it
整整一周，君子一言，駟馬難追
I'll buy some candles and keep them lit day and night
我會去買些蠟燭 然後讓它們白天夜晚都不熄滅
You'll go straight to heaven, ma' am
你一定會直接上天堂的，女士
- It's a sacrifice for me - I can imagine
- 這對於我真的是一個大犧牲 - 我可以想像
But I'll do it gladly
不過，我仍然很願意這樣做
I'll lose about... 200,000 lire
我會損失大概，200000里拉
Goodness, you earn that much?
上帝，你掙得這麼多
I could make more if I wanted, but I only see who I like
如果我想我還能掙更多 不過我只挑我喜歡的
You're right
你是對的
Who's speaking? Yes, this is Miss Mara's home
是哪位，這裡是瑪莎女士的家
No, she's gone away. She'll be back at Christmas
沒有，她出門去了 她會在聖誕節的時候回來
- Cheers!
- 乾杯
- Who was it? - A Sicilian... see soon.
- 誰的電話 - 一個西西里的，回頭見
No, come and talk to the lady. Like a Strega?
別走，進來和夫人聊聊
- Where are you going? - I'll be back
- 你要去哪裡 - 我會回來的
Sorry I interrupted you
對不起，我打斷你們了
Don't mention it
別介意
This girl is an angel
這個姑娘是個天使
Yes, she's good. See you later
是的，她很好，回頭見
No. Pour the lady another drink
別走，給這位女士再倒杯酒
Goodness no, my head's going round
上帝保佑別這樣了，我已經醉的有點暈了
You know I never had any grandparents?
你知道嗎我沒有奶奶
Strange
怎麼會沒有
I wish I'd had a granny like you. And you?
我希望我有個像你這樣的奶奶，你呢
I have three grandparents
我有三個奶奶
No!
不會吧
Yes. Goodbye
是這樣的，再見
I'm glad I met you
見到你很榮幸
So am I
我也很榮幸
Don't slam the door!
關門的時候別摔門
Where were you born?
你是哪裡人
We're all from Lucania
我們都是從路卡尼亞來的
I'm from Anticoli... Anticoli Romano
我是從安帝克麗來的安帝克麗洛曼諾
Can I help you?
我能為您效勞嗎
Yes, look, I'd like six of these nice candles
請給我六根那樣的蠟燭
Hey, what are you doing there?
你在這幹什麼
Come in!
進來
- How much? - 1,800 lire
- 多少錢 - 1800里拉
- Any discount? - No
- 打折嗎 - 沒有折扣
- Where have you sprung from? - I was just passing
- 你從哪裡冒出來的 - 我只是路過而已
Can I buy you a present?
我能給你買個禮物嗎
This would suit you
這件修道服一定很適合你
How much is this?
多少錢
18,000 lire
18000里拉
What do I do with it?
我要它幹什麼
What a question! Keep it as a memento
真是傻問題，當然留作紀念用
Wear it when you're a priest
當你成為修道士的時候穿上它
You're in league with Gran
你是在幫奶奶說話嗎
She's an angel, leave her out of it
她是位天使般的女士，這事和她無關
Pay at the desk
請到收銀台付款
Last night I had a vision... Saint Maurillo
昨晚，我看到了一個景象聖毛利洛
What were you thinking of? You know I could be your mother?
你到底在想什麼 你知道我都可以當你的媽媽了
Come on, try this on
過來，試試這件
This would really suit you!
這件肯定很適合你
You weren't born for those clothes
你生來就不是穿這種衣服的
I fell for an officer once, his uniform really turned me on
我曾經愛上過一個警官 他的制服吸引我難以自拔
When he put on civilian clothes
當他穿上便服的時候
he looked like a plucked chicken
他看起來就像一隻無精打采的母雞
Must you put them there?
你必須把它們扔掉
Don't you have any faith? You know who they're for?
你難道沒有信仰嗎，你知道信仰為何物嗎
Sure
我當然知道
Better put them out now though
現在最好把它們熄滅掉
You're right
說得對
- Do you have any Coca Cola? - Yes
- 你家裡有可口可樂嗎 - 有
- And eggs?
- 雞蛋呢
- What day is it today? - Thursday
- 今天禮拜幾 - 禮拜四
We'll surface on Saturday, we'll stay put till them
我們一直到禮拜六 我們呆在這兒知道禮拜六
The phone!
電話
My father's due to call
我爸爸會打電話來
- What is it? - The blinds!
- 怎麼了 - 百葉窗
Ma'am!
女士
- Who is it? Gran? - No, the wind
- 那是誰，奶奶嗎 - 沒人，是風
Out of the way
走開走開
He wants to join the Foreign Legion. He's packing!
他要去加入海外軍團，他正在打包
We must stop him, he's gone mad!
我們必須要阻止他，他瘋了
I'm coming... Rusconi! Come here!
我來了，博洛尼亞，快過來
Help me climb over
幫我爬過去
Come on!
快來
- Give it to me! - No
- 給我 - 不給
Let me be! Naughty boy!
讓我來，你這個不聽話的孩子
What are you up to?
你想要幹什麼
Tell him I'm not a liar, that I told him the truth
告訴他我沒有說謊，我告訴他的都是真的
Your gran told the truth
你奶奶說的都是真的
The whole truth
全部都是真的
Why do you want to make me feel guilty? I never have before
你為什麼讓我有罪惡感 我以前從未有過這樣的罪惡感
The seminary is a secure life. Food, a bed, and you're out...
在學校學習是一條光明的路 食物，住宿，結果你卻想要離開…
of this wicked world! I'd be a nun if I had another life
到這個污穢的世界來 如果我能選擇我會去當一個修女
Give me the case!
把行李箱給我
You're hurting, Umberto!
你弄疼我了，翁貝托
I want to go away!
我要遠走高飛
Rusconi! Come on out!
博洛尼亞，快出來
Don't just stand there, come on!
別只站著，快過來
Come on, hurry!
過來，快點
What are you up to, boy?
你到底想怎麼樣，孩子
Give me that case! Come on!
把行李箱給我，快點
Mr Rusconi...
博洛尼亞先生
- Villenzone - Pleased to meet you
- 文森佐 - 見到你很高興
- Sit down - Thank you
- 請坐 - 謝謝
You tell him that I wasn't lying
你告訴他我說的都是實話
That nobody should be trousted except parents and grandparents
在這個世界上除了父母和祖父母 再沒有人是可以被信任的了
Is it true you make more than a million a month?
你真的一個月掙不止一百萬
It's true
是真的
Hear that? He wouldn't believe me, he said I made it up
聽到沒，他不相信，他說是我編的謊言
But keep it to yourself or the tax-man will hear about it
不過請守口如瓶，如果讓稅務檢察官聽到了
And try telling him the family eats most of your money!
就告訴他們他一個人養活全家人 沒有餘下的錢了
The train leaves at 5
火車五點鐘開車
We'll take him to the station. Rusconi has his car
我們把他送到車站吧，博洛尼亞有車
If we go now there's a bus
如果我們現在走的話能趕上巴士
There's a bus, I've seen it
巴士在那，我剛剛看到了
Umberto understands the situation. Don't you, boy?
翁貝托你明不明白，明白了嗎
I'm not a boy!
我不是小孩了
He's right
他說的對
What are you crying for? You people are always crying
你哭什麼 你們一家人怎麼總是哭泣啊
Yes, son, cry
哭吧，哭吧孩子
The Lord answered my prayers...
上帝回應了我的祈禱…
Thank you, ma'am... thank you!
女士，謝謝你
There they are!
他們在那
After you, Reverend
等一下，牧師
I'm so happy! You should be happy too, you did a good deed
我好開心啊，你也應該和我一樣開心 我們做了一件大好事
Yes, my conscience is clear
對啊，我的心情好輕鬆呢
Who cares about the soccer match!
管它的呢
Close the blinds
把百葉窗關上吧
I won't budge from here, I'll stay in your bed forever!
我再也不要從這離開了 我要永遠呆在你的床上
I'll put roots down!
我要在這兒扎根
Don't shout
別嚎
Put a record on. Undress, I'll watch you from here
把音樂打開吧，脫衣服，我要在這兒看你脫
We can't!
我們不能
We have to wait a week
我們必須要等到下周
What...?
什麼
I'm sorry, I can't help it
對不起，我真的沒辦法
What do you mean?
你什麼意思
Don't look like that, try to understand
別那樣看著我，能不能理解理解我
I made a vow
我發誓了
Understand?!
明白嗎
I'll start crying too now
我現在也要哭了
You want to drive me crazy
你要把我變瘋嗎
But sweetheart, a vow is a vow
可是親愛的，誓言就是誓言
It's all over between us!
我們之間結束了
A week is soon over
只要一周而已啊
You won't see me again! I'm a responsible person, not a child!
你永遠不會再見到我了 我是一個說話算話的人，我不是孩子了
Can't you make a sacrifice?
你難道就不能忍耐一下嗎
It'll be even better after. Come on, I'll fix you a coffee
過了這段時間之後肯定會更好的 來吧，我給你泡杯咖啡
Forget coffee! Here's your wallet back
別泡了，給你錢
And the tie! And the handkerchief!
還有你的領帶，還有你送的手絹
But why? Don't be like that
為什麼呀，別這樣麼
I drove 300 miles
我開車開了三百哩才到這兒
Be serious!
認真點
I am serious. It's you who isn't serious
我是認真的，你才不認真呢
Came on...
來嘛
Do you feel up to committing sacrilege?
你難道不覺得這樣是褻瀆嗎
If you're not scared, come on!
如果你害怕褻瀆，那你就進來吧
But I'll be like a block of marble.
不過我就會像石頭堆裡面的石頭 那樣毫無反應
It'll be your responsibility
而且你要付全部責任
You could have made the vow for next month. You knew I was here
你可以發誓說誓言下個月生效啊 你也知道我等了多久
Yes no, yes no since yesterday. It's bad for one's health!
可以，不行，可以，不行，從昨天開始 就這樣，這樣對我的健康也不好啊
Bologna!
博洛尼亞
Yes, this is 577000. Bologna?
對，這裡是577000，博洛尼亞
Yes, it's me, Dad
是的，是我，爸爸
We have to wait awhile longer, it still needs stamping
我們必須要等得再久一店，因為公章的問題
No...
不
I'm flying back tonight
我今晚坐飛機回去
I've done everything I had to do
我已經盡全力做了所有我能做的事
I even handed out the tips
我甚至都已經行賄了
But you have to tip them in advance, Dad!
不過為了早點也不得不行賄的，爸爸
Come here
過來
No, I'm going
不，我得走了
Keep me company... He'll get you the permit
陪陪我吧，他也能聽到你的祈禱的
Don't be like that
別這個樣子
Come on, Augusto, come here...
過來，阿古斯，過來嘛…